Summary

Software programmer with experience supporting enterprise level software operation, development, and training. Comfortable working with the high priority demands of medical practices across a wide variety of specialties. Adaptable to unique software implementations and proficient in popular business database development techniques.

Skills

Programming experience

Microsoft SQL Server 2005, 2008, 2012 T-SQL, DTS, SSRS, SSIS C / C++ / C# Ruby, Rails Framework Crystal Reports XIV Health Level 7 Interfaces HTML, XML, CSS

Software used frequently

SQL Server Management Studio
Microsoft Visual Studio
SVN, TortoiseSVN, Git
Microsoft Office Suite (Word, Excel, Outlook)
Windows (2000, XP, 7, 10)
Linux (Ubuntu, Debian)
NextGen (EHR/EMR, ICS, Template Editor, Rosetta)
Mirth Connect

Individual Accomplishments

- Presented multiple years at NextGen Healthcare's yearly conference during the Client Innovation Contest and Ignite sessions.
- Designed an enterprise solution for health care facilities to efficiently interface medical providers with their patients by allowing secure messaging.
- Defined the process for tracking customer contract utilization allowing for additional revenue to be generated when development over contract limits was requested.
- Developed a web application dashboard that would allow administrative monitoring of application usage.

Experience

2010-Current Developer

NextCare Urgent Care

Mesa, AZ / Memphis, TN

NextGen application developer in charge of the design and development of templates for the NextGen patient user interface by using both clinical and IT knowledge. Developer is responsible for quality assurance, template process analysis for improvement, and correcting all known issues. Essential functions include:

- Implemented an agile change management process and software Kanban solution used by departments with ownership of the core business product, NextGen Ambulatory.
- Scoped and created a custom C# application to present business critical information to all employees prior to accessing core business software. The application is fully managed by medical operations and training teams.
- Lead weekly planning meetings with medical operation, training and education, and development team to coordinate announcements and software deployments.
- Lead weekly sprint meetings with development team.
- Established and maintained a strict version controlled environment and seamlessly integrated it with the change management software solution such that all code check-ins are associated with a trackable change request.
- Designed and built from scratch a Ruby on Rails web application that allowed authorized individuals to lookup patients across all business units fulfilling the company need for a master patient index.
- Navigated the ICD10 government mandate, by designing and executing a custom ICD9 to ICD10 conversion.
- Developed from scratch a C# application used to deliver Crystal Reports via email or file export autonomously based on preselected delivery schedule.
- Utilized SQL Server and Crystal Reporting techniques to pull atypical data requested by various departments for data analysis and audit purposes.

- Collaborated as a development team to edit and maintain the NextGen EHR Knowledge Base of templates.
- Mentored junior developer through the "watch one, do one, teach one" method. By meeting weekly, we were able to offer continual feedback and new skill development in the following ways:
 - Took a hands-off coaching role in colleague's first C# application built for the purpose of allowing training department to simulate electronically received lab and diagnostics results from an interfaced third party system. This allowed for authentic training scenarios for onboarding clinical staff.
 - Introduced and provided samples of professional documentation processes.
 - Re-enforcing proper code documentation and use case testing.
 - Introduced writing SQL basic queries and progressively advanced colleague's talent up to the point of being comfortable writing custom stored procedures unaided.
 - Provided peer review of code check-in differentials to help detect any possible defects, prevent unintended downstream impacts, and optimize where necessary.
- Performed peer review and formal design reviews as part of the release cycle.
- Remediated findings highlighted by external security audit.
- Integrated medical claims clearing house with core practice management software by accessing vendors' secure FTP systems.
- Connected to laboratory, radiology, and insurance carrier systems across TCP/IP, SOAP and HTTPS to transmit and receive structured document, demographics, order, and result messages.
- Developed a custom C# application used by internal IT support staff in response to a recurring licensing issue which prevented users from accessing the NextGen software.
- On an as needed basis, worked with advanced end users for beta testing new features.

2009-2010 InforMed / SergeMD Memphis, TN

Product Developer

Web developer to work with engineering team to create and publish web application to integrate with existing customer software services. Activities included:

- Designed an enterprise solution for health care facilities to efficiently interface medical providers with their patients by allowing secure messaging.
- Designed a web application that would allow administrative monitoring of application usage allowing for a single point of entry.
- Defined project milestones as defined by statement of work agreements.
- Operated within a version control infrastructure.
- Initiated internal product demonstrations for team leads and sales executives to equip staff to properly support and advertise value added features and functionality.

2008-2009 InforMed / SergeMD Memphis, TN

Software Developer

Template developer to create and edit forms and documents in NextGen and Crystal Reports software, use SQL stored procedures to enhance system functionality, perform NextGen software upgrades and migrations, perform NextGen associated software updates and implementations, and correspond with clients regarding software changes. Activities included:

- Provided top-level, application specific technical support.
- Defined the process for tracking customer contract utilization allowing for additional revenue to be generated when excessive development was requested.
- Performed client-contracted quarterly and billable development tasks.
- Designed a SQL job that would notify support staff of abnormal application operation. This automated a daily task that had required staff to check up to 6 applications on 12 servers.
- Updated the software with the current versions of ICD-9, CPT-4, patient education, medication, allergy, and drug interaction tables.
- Scheduled and performed routine software maintenance roll outs.
- Perform KBM upgrades, patches and conversions for the template sets utilized by the practice.
- Worked as the team lead to implement interfaces between NextGen and 3rd party systems including reference labs, radiology vendors, and EKG equipment reducing staffing and eliminating data entry requirements.

- Communicated with all levels of end users including front desk, administrative, nursing, and providers.
- Authored content published to the corporate website promoting the department's professional services.

2006-2008 InforMed / SergeMD Memphis, TN

Technical Support

Level 1 technician to monitor and maintain the computer systems and networks of enterprise. Install, configure, and troubleshoot computer systems running a variety of hardware and software problems. Activities included:

- Functioned as primary point of contact for customers.
- Defined support procedure by documenting processes and publishing to a corporate repository.
- Documented customer problems utilizing corporate issue tracking software.
- Coordinated communications between customers and third party vendors.
- Managed on-call services for technical support after office hours.
- Worked in Active Directory to create and maintain user profiles, resolve password issues.
- Remotely managed application servers running critical background processes.
- Conducted site surveys to inventory client hardware.

Education

2001-2006 University of Tennessee at Knoxville

Knoxville, TN

Computer Engineering

Engineering classes focused on digital image processing. Senior level projects included:

- Worked with a graduate level study on a defense department contract. We designed a software system to be used by border patrol to identify shipping vessels. Work was done in MATLAB.
- Designed and manufactured a small scale traffic simulation. Programmed in assembly language and burned to a FPGA ROM and connected with circuit board controls.

Computer science classes focused on systems programming in C/C++ utilizing public libraries created by the professor.

Other Technical Skills

Experienced in complete PC assembly. Optimized custom PC builds by overclocking timings and tuning voltages. Custom home network setup with onsite webserver and Raspberry PI DNS black hole.